safeco.com 2018-06-29

# Consumer Privacy Policy | Safeco Insurance

Effective Date: 12/15/2010 

Safeco appreciates the trust you place in us when you purchase insurance from one of our companies. We are committed to protecting your nonpublic personal information ("personal information") and we value you as a customer. 

To learn more about how Safeco collects and uses your personal information, please read the following notice. 

Safeco's Sources of Information About You

We collect personal information about you from different sources, including:

  * The information you provide on applications or other forms (such as your name, address, and Social Security number).
  * Your transactions with us, our affiliates or others (such as your payment history and claims information).
  * The information we receive from a consumer reporting agency or insurance support organization (such as your credit history, driving record, or claims history).
  * Your independent insurance distributor (such as updated information pertaining to your account).

Safeco's Use of Your Personal Information

We only disclose personal information about our customers and former customers as permitted by law. Generally, this includes disclosures to third parties to effect, administer or enforce your transactions with us, or in connection with servicing your insurance policy. These third parties may include independent insurance producers authorized to sell Safeco insurance products, independent contractors (such as automobile repair facilities and property inspectors), independent claims representatives, insurance support organizations, auditors, attorneys, courts, and government agencies. We may also disclose your personal information to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. Before disclosing your personal information, we require these parties to enter into an agreement with us that includes a confidentiality provision. 

We may also share information about our transactions (such as payment history and products purchased) and experiences (such as claims made) with you within our Safeco family of companies. Safeco does not sell your personal information to others and we do not provide your information to third parties for their own marketing purposes. 

The independent insurance agents and brokers authorized to sell Safeco products and services are not Safeco employees and are not subject to Safeco`s Privacy Policy. Because they have a unique business relationship with you, they may have additional personal information about you that Safeco does not have. They may use this information differently than Safeco. Contact your Safeco agent or broker to learn more about their privacy practices. 

Information About Safeco Websites and Applications

The following provisions apply to your use of our website, Safeco.com, and to your use of the Safeco app for Apple iOS (our "App"). 

Information collected

We collect personal information (for example, name, address, e-mail address) on our website and through the App only when you voluntarily provide it to us. Only your domain is recognized when you visit our website; your individual e-mail address is not. The web analytics services Safeco uses anonymously and automatically record the date and time you access our web systems (either through our website or our App), your location (if enabled on your Apple iOS device), and the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the website from where you came (if any). It may also track the pages you viewed on, or pages or functions you accessed from, our website or our App. These statistics help us to better understand how our website and our App are being used and what we can do to make them more useful to visitors and users. The information that we collect is used to improve the content of our website and our App and to improve our service to you and other consumers. 

Information Sharing and Use

Safeco does not sell information about you to others. If you only browse our website or use our App, and do not supply any information, you will not receive unsolicited e-mail, telephone calls, or other marketing materials from Safeco as a result of your visit. 

When you make changes to your account or request more information about our products, we may forward information that you supply to us to your independent Safeco insurance agent or broker. We do this so they can service your account or contact you with additional information about our products. 

Cookies

Our website sends cookies to your computer. We use cookies to carry forward information you entered on one page to other pages you visit. The data in the cookies we serve can be used only by our website and do not contain your personal information. Our cookies do not read data from your computer's hard disk or other websites' cookies. Safeco does not serve or use cookies that store and track your visits to other websites. 

Browsers & Security

We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology on some of the pages in our web site. SSL protects information as it crosses the Internet. When using our website, you can tell if you are visiting a secure area by looking at the padlock symbol at the bottom of your browser screen. If it is "locked," you have a secure session. Safeco has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of your personal information. Our servers are located in the United States of America and are designed to prevent unauthorized access. 

Links to Other Sites

Safeco.com and our App contain links to third party websites. These websites are not under Safeco's direct control, and they may collect information about you that Safeco does not. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of linked websites. 

Protecting Your Personal Information From Unauthorized Access

We maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect your personal information. Our employees are authorized to access customer information only for legitimate business purposes. 

Your Medical Information

If Safeco obtains medical information about you, it is done only in connection with specific claims. We will not use or share personally identifiable medical information for any purpose other than the administration of your claim or as otherwise disclosed to you when the information is collected. 

Reviewing Your Information

You can request a copy of the information about you that we have in our files to review it for completeness and accuracy. Your request must be in writing. Please contact your insurance distributor or nearest local Safeco office for a mailing address. Within 30 business days (or as required by law) of receiving your written request, we will send you the information. 

Changes to This Statement

Please be aware that we may periodically update or revise this Statement. Please check our Consumer Privacy Statement frequently for changes. 

This Privacy Statement applies to the following members of the Safeco family of companies: 

  * American Economy Insurance Company
  * American States Insurance Company
  * American States Insurance Company of Texas
  * American States Lloyds Insurance Company
  * American States Preferred Insurance Company
  * First National Insurance Company of America
  * General Insurance Company of America
  * Insurance Company of Illinois
  * Liberty County Mutual Insurance Company
  * Safeco Insurance Company of America
  * Safeco Insurance Company of Illinois
  * Safeco Insurance Company of Indiana
  * Safeco Insurance Company of Oregon
  * Safeco Lloyds Insurance Company
  * Safeco National Insurance Company
  * Safeco Surplus Lines Insurance Company
  * Employers Insurance Company of Wausau
